# Jose Guzman

# Full-Stack Web Developer

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Javascript, JQuery, PHP

Node Js, Express, React Js

Firebase, MongoDB, SQL

AJAX, JSON, RESTful APIs

EJS, Pug, Handlebars

IBM-Watson

## PERSONAL SKILLS

Outstanding Math skills

Goal Orientated

Fast Learner

Problem Solver

Google Foo

### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Jose Guzman Kissimmee FL 34743

T: 407-361-6298

E:jguzman24680@gmail.com

Portfolio:

https://snowghost24.github.io/Portfolio4/

Github:

https://github.com/snowghost24

## **SUMMARY**

A highly resourceful, innovative, and competent full-stack developer experienced in both front-end and back-end development of web applications. Experienced in the development of web applications using a variety in script languages, database languages, and artificial intelligence.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Secondary Math Teacher – Wilby High School** 08/2009 – 06/2015 Taught Geometry, Algebra I & II, and Pre-Calculus to students in grades 9-12.

*Administrative Assistance – SPS National Lab* 06/2016 – 01/2017 Managed billing, data entry and maintaining communication with outside clients

#### RELEVENT EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer – Orlando Florida 08/2017 - Present Worked with clients and met requirements for the functional elements of website

projects while ensuring that all work carried out to standards and best practices. Consulted clients

## KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Front-end layouts and design using HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap 3&4
- Creating responsive layouts with and without bootstrap
- Developing advanced database driven websites SQL and MongoDB using PHP and Node Js.
- Developing and making accessible RESTful API's
- Developing compatible user interface functionality using jQuery & other libraries.
- Developing Node applications with Handlebars, EJS, PUG templating engines
- Developing Node applications using React JS for user interface.
- Create a full stack Single Page Application with AJAX communication
- Created chat-bots and voice command assistance

#### APPLICATIONS BUILT

## **Voice Command App**

- Built using IBM-Watson conversation service this application allows you to add styling to the applications, send emails, post tweets, and retrieve housing data from Zillow all using voice command (under construction)
- See Github for directions Link: <a href="https://github.com/snowghost24/finalProject">https://github.com/snowghost24/finalProject</a>
- Link: <a href="https://voice-assistance.herokuapp.com/">https://voice-assistance.herokuapp.com/</a>

# Curriculum-It

- This app allows you to keep track of courses. After login you can create a
  course, enroll in course, move to in progress and complete the course. The
  courses are stored in a SQL database.
- I was responsible for creating the login/log and the ORMs
- See Github: https://github.com/snowghost24/Curriculum-it
- Link: https://whispering-garden-26491.herokuapp.com/

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

Full-Stack Developer Certificate *University of Central Florida* 

Completed **09//2017 – 11/2017** 

Master of Arts in Mathematics

Western Connecticut State University

06/2012 - 12/2015

Bachelor's of Science in Economics